https://www.burgmann.act.edu.au/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
HomePrivacy PolicyPrivacy Policy
This Privacy Policy details how we protect your privacy and how we comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act
and the 13 Australian Privacy Principles, as well as the requirements
of Health Records (Privacy and Access) Act (ACT) (“the Health Privacy
Principles). This policy also describes:
who we collect information from;the types of personal information collected and held by us;how this information is collected and held;the purposes for which your personal information is collected, held, used and disclosed;how you can gain access to your personal information and seek its correction;how you may complain or inquire about
our collection, handling, use or disclosure of your personal information
and how that complaint or inquiry will be handled; andwhether we are likely to disclose your personal information to any overseas recipients.Who do we Collect Personal Information From?At Burgmann Anglican School we collect
personal information from students, parents, prospective parents, job
applicants, staff, volunteers and others including alumni, contractors,
visitors and others that come into contact with the school.It is noted that employee records are not
covered by the Australian Privacy Principles or the Health Privacy
Principles where they relate to current or former employment relations
between the school and the employee.What Kinds of Personal Information Do We Collect?The kinds of personal information we
collect is largely dependent upon whose information we are collecting
and why we are collecting it, however in general terms the school may
collect:Personal Information
including names, addresses and other contact details; dates of birth;
next of kin details; financial information, photographic images and
attendance records.Sensitive Information
(particularly in relation to student and parent records) including
religious beliefs, government identifiers, nationality, country of
birth, languages spoken at home, professional or union memberships,
family court orders and criminal records.Health Information
(particularly in relation to student and parent records) including
medical records, disabilities, immunisation details, individual health
care plans, counselling reports, nutrition and dietary requirements.How do we collect your personal information?How we collect personal information will
largely be dependent upon whose information we are collecting. If it is
reasonable and practical to do so, we collect personal information
directly from you.Where possible the school has attempted to
standardise the collection of personal information by using
specifically designed forms (e.g. an Enrolment Form or a Health
Information Disclosure Form). However, given the nature of our
operations, we often also receive personal information by email,
letters, notes, over the telephone, in face to face meetings, through
financial transactions and through surveillance activities such as the
use of CCTV security cameras or email monitoring.We may also collect personal information
from other people (e.g. a personal reference) or independent sources
(e.g. a telephone directory), however we will only do so where it is not
reasonable and practical to collect the information from you directly.Sometimes we may be provided with your
personal information without having sought it through our normal means
of collection. We refer to this as “unsolicited information”. Where we
collect unsolicited information we will only hold, use and/or disclose
that information if we could otherwise do so had we collected it by
normal means. If that unsolicited information could not have been
collected by normal means then we will destroy, permanently delete or
de-identify the information as appropriate.How we use personal informationWe only use personal information that is
reasonably necessary for one or more of our functions or activities (the
primary purpose) or for a related secondary purpose that would be
reasonably expected by you, or to which you have consented.Our primary uses of personal information include but are not limited to:providing education, pastoral care, extra-curricular and health services;satisfying our legal obligations including our duty of care and child protection obligations;keeping parents informed as to school community matters through correspondence, newsletters and magazines;marketing, promotional and fundraising activities;supporting the activities of school associations such as Burgmann Anglican School P&F Association;supporting community based causes and
activities, charities and other causes in connection with the School’s
functions or activities;helping us to improve our day to day
operations including training our staff; systems development; developing
new programs and services; undertaking planning, research and
statistical analysis;school administration including for insurance purposes;the employment of staff;the engagement of volunteers.We only collect sensitive information
reasonably necessary for one or more of these functions or activities,
if we have the consent of the individuals to whom the sensitive
information relates, or if the collection is necessary to lessen or
prevent a serious threat to life, health or safety, or another permitted
general situation (such as locating a missing person) or permitted
health situation (such as the collection of health information to
provide a health service) exists.If we do not have the relevant consent and
a permitted health situation or permitted general situation does not
exist, then we may still collect sensitive information provided it
relates solely to individuals who have regular contact with the school
in connection with our activities. These individuals may include
students, parents, volunteers, former students and other individuals
with whom the school has regular contact in relation to our activities.We will only use or disclose sensitive
information for a secondary purpose if you would reasonably expect us to
use or disclose the information and the secondary purpose is directly
related to the primary purpose.Storage and Security of Personal InformationWe store personal information in a variety
of formats including on databases, in hard copy files and on personal
devices including laptop computers, mobile phones, cameras and other
recording devices.The security of your personal information
is of importance to us and we take all reasonable steps to protect the
personal information we hold about you from misuse, loss, unauthorised
access, modification or disclosure.These steps include:Restricting access to information on the
school databases on a need to know basis with different levels of
security being allocated to staff based on their roles and
responsibilities and security profile.Ensuring all staff are aware that they are not to reveal or share personal passwords.Ensuring where sensitive and health
information is stored in hard copy files that these files are stored in
lockable filing cabinets in lockable rooms. Access to these records is
restricted to staff on a need to know basis.Implementing physical security measures around the school buildings and grounds to prevent break-ins.Implementing ICT security systems,
policies and procedures, designed to protect personal information
storage on our computer networks.Implementing human resources policies
and procedures, such as email and internet usage, confidentiality and
document security policies, designed to ensure that staff follow correct
protocols when handling personal information.Undertaking due diligence with respect
to third party service providers who may have access to personal
information, including cloud service providers, to ensure as far as
practicable that they are compliant with the Australian Privacy
Principles or a similar privacy regime.Personal information we hold that is no longer needed is destroyed in a secure manner, deleted or de-identified as appropriate.Our website may contain links to other
websites. We do not share your personal information with those websites
and we are not responsible for their privacy practices. Please check
their privacy policies.Responding to data breachesBurgmann Anglican School will take appropriate, prompt action if we
have reasonable grounds to believe that a data breach may have, or is
suspected to have occurred. Depending on the type of data breach, this
may include a review of our internal security procedures, taking
remedial internal action, notifying affected individuals and the Office
of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC).If we are unable to notify individuals, we will publish a statement
on our website and take reasonable steps to publicise the contents of
this statement.When we disclose personal informationWe only use personal information for the
purposes for which it was given to us, or for purposes which are related
(or directly related in the case of sensitive information) to one or
more of our functions or activities. We may disclose your personal
information to government agencies, other parents, other schools,
recipients of school publications, visiting teachers, counsellors and
coaches, our service providers, agents, contractors, business partners
and other recipients from time to time, only if one or more of the
following apply:you have consented;you would reasonably expect us to use or disclose your personal information in this way;we are authorised or required to do so by law;disclosure will lessen or prevent a serious threat to the life, health or safety of an individual or to public safety;where another permitted general situation or permitted health situation exception applies;disclosure is reasonably necessary for a law enforcement related activity.Personal Information of Students The Privacy Act does not differentiate
between adults and children and does not specify an age after which
individuals can make their own decisions with respect to their personal
information.At Burgmann Anglican School we take a
common sense approach to dealing with a student’s personal information
and generally will refer any requests for personal information to a
student’s parents/carers. We will treat notices provided to
parents/carers as notices provided to students and we will treat
consents provided by parents/carers as consents provided by a student.We are however cognisant of the fact that
children do have rights under the Privacy Act, and that in certain
circumstances (especially when dealing with older students and
especially when dealing with sensitive information), it will be
appropriate to seek and obtain consents directly from students. We also
acknowledge that there may be occasions where a student may give or
withhold consent with respect to the use of their personal information
independently from their parents/carers.There may also be occasions where
parents/carers are denied access to information with respect to their
children, because to provide such information would have an unreasonable
impact on the privacy of others, or result in a breach of the school’s
duty of care to the student.Disclosure of personal information to overseas recipientsWe may disclose personal information about
an individual to overseas recipients in certain circumstances, such as
when we are organising an overseas excursion, facilitating a student
exchange, or storing information with a “cloud computing service” which
stores data outside of Australia. We will however take all reasonable
steps not to disclose an individual’s personal information to overseas
recipients unless:We have the individual’s consent (which may be implied); orWe have satisfied ourselves that the
overseas recipient is compliant with the Australian Privacy Principles,
or a similar privacy regime; orWe form the opinion that the disclosure
will lessen or prevent a serious threat to the life, health or safety of
an individual or to public safety; orWe are taking appropriate action in relation to suspected unlawful activity or serious misconductHow we ensure the quality of your personal informationWe take all reasonable steps to ensure the
personal information we hold, use and disclose is accurate, complete
and up to date. These steps include ensuring that the personal
information is accurate, complete and up to date at the time of
collection and when using or disclosing the personal information. On an
ongoing basis we maintain and update personal information when we are
advised by individuals or when we become aware through other means that
their personal information has changed.Please contact us if any of the details
you have provided change. You should also contact us if you believe that
the information we have about you is not accurate, complete or up to
date.How to gain access to your personal information we holdYou may request access to the personal
information we hold about you, or request that we change the personal
information, by contacting us.If we do not agree to provide you with
access, or to amend your personal information as requested, you will be
notified accordingly. Where appropriate we will provide you with the
reason/s for our decision. If the rejection relates to a request to
change your personal information you may make a statement about the
requested change and we will attach this to your record.Privacy ComplaintsIf you wish to make a complaint about a
breach by us of the Australian Privacy Principles or the Health Privacy
Principles you may do so by providing your written complaint by email,
letter, facsimile or by personal delivery to any one of our contact
details as noted below. You may also make a complaint verbally.We will respond to your complaint within a
reasonable time (usually no longer than 30 days) and we may seek
further information from you in order to provide a full and complete
response.Your complaint may also be taken to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.How to Contact UsYou can contact us about this Policy or about your personal information by:Emailing PrivacyOfficer@burgmann.act.edu.auCalling 02 6255 7700Writing to our Privacy Officer: Joel Anderson,  at 4 The Valley Avenue, Gungahlin, ACT 2912If practical, you can contact us
anonymously (i.e. without identifying yourself) or by using a pseudonym.
However, if you choose not to identify yourself, we may not be able to
give you the information or provide the assistance you might otherwise
receive if it is not practical to do so.This Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time. Please check our Privacy Policy on our website www.burgmann.act.edu.au  regularly for any changes.This Privacy Policy was last reviewed: 22nd February 2018
